谢谢你让我的索尼克成为你的索尼克。
Thank you for making my Sonic your Sonic.
我叫麦凯拉。今晚有什么可以帮您的吗?
My name is McKayla. How can I help you tonight?
我要一份一英尺奶酪科尼加芥末和洋葱，大罐土豆泥和一大杯樱桃酸橙汁。
I need a Footlong Cheese Coney with mustard and onions, large Tots and a large Cherry Limeade.
我们在路上向人们展示OxiClean的抗污能力。
We're on the road showing real people the stain-fighting power of OxiClean.
主啊，谢谢你，为这一切祝福。
Thank you, Lord, for this and many other blessings.
请看好艾丽。
Please keep a watchful eye over Ally.
以耶稣的名义。阿们。
In Jesus' name. Amen.
你知道这有多烦人吗?
Do you know how annoying that is?
更不用说那样你的眼睛会被炸掉。
Not to mention you could blow out your eye that way.
-你来自哪里?——静水。
- Where you from? - Stillwater.
你上一个为哪家钻井公司工作?
Who's the last drilling company you worked for?
- ITA。-你为什么辞职?
- ITA. - Why'd you quit?
操作人员丢下钻机。我们堆放。
Operator dropped the rig. We stacked.
我六个月前被解雇了。
I got laid off six months ago.
你现在在做什么?
What are you doing now?
我在建筑业工作。
I work construction.
但自从钻井平台被毁后就一直很慢。
But it's been slow since the rig's been down.
肖尼龙卷风之后我一直在清理。
I've been doing cleanup after that tornado by Shawnee.
得到后。
Getting after it.
嘿,沙龙。
Hey, Sharon.
让我把这页读完。
Let me finish this page.
再读一页。
One more page.
谢谢你给我的食物和这世界上一切美好的东西。
Thank you for this food and for all that is good in this world.
要时刻注意艾莉森。
Keep Allison in your watchful eye.
——阿门。——阿门。
- Amen. - Amen.
你被录用了吗?
You get hired out yet?
不。
Nope.
今天早上有个面试。
Had an interview this morning.
几天前接到你妈妈的电话。
Got a call from your mother a few days ago.
她搬到了坦帕。
She moved to Tampa.
她是要钱还是什么?
She ask for money or some shit?
不。
No.
她问起你。
She asked about you.
你应该给她打个电话。
You should call her sometime.
我已经够忙的了。
I got enough I'm dealing with here.
你拿到我的车牌号了吗?
Did you pick up my car registration?
是的。
Yeah.
我在家里买的。
I got it at home.
我等了一上午。
Spent all morning waiting for it.
在网上找到的。
Got it online.
一切的在线。
Everything's online.
就算你想，也找不到一个真正的人。
Can't get a real human being if you try.
没能阻止他们收我23美元。
Didn't stop them from charging me $23.
我会支付的。
I'll pay it.
我不是那个意思。
That's not what I meant.
我知道。
I know.
前门旁边有一包东西让你拿。
There's a bag of things by the front door for you to take.
还有一个装着照片的信封放在她桌上。
And an envelope of photos in on her desk.
这些是很重要的。
Those are important.
你有两次中途停留，第一次在亚特兰大，第二次在法兰克福。
Okay, you have two stopovers, the first in Atlanta, the second in Frankfurt.
-你在22号门。——谢谢。
- You're at gate 22. - Thank you.
我只需要你的签名。
I just need your signature please.
-你要和我们在一起两周?——是的,女士。
- You are with us for two weeks? - Yes, ma'am.
谢谢。
Thanks.
这是你的钥匙。156房间。
Here's your key. Room 156.
谢谢你,女士。
Thank you, ma'am.
欢迎回来，贝克先生。
Welcome back, Mr. Baker.
嘿。
Hey.
哦,原谅。
Oh, pardon.
谢谢。
Merci.
嘿。嘿。
Hey. Hey.
你们能小声点吗?我要睡觉了。
Y'all mind keeping it down? I'm trying to sleep.
——音乐。——嗯?
- The music. - Hein?
没有英语。
No-no English.
不讲英语。
No speak English.
是的,好的。
Yeah, all right.
嘿,晚安。
Hey, good night.
-你好。-贝克。
- Bonjour. - Baker.
萨利姆,九桥。
Salim, neuf.
穆萨,迪克斯。
Moussa, dix.
贝克,onze。
Baker, onze.
谢谢。
Merci.
-嘿，宝贝。——嗨,爸爸。
- Hey, baby girl. - Hey, Dad.
你看起来很好。
You look good.
谢谢。
Thanks.
飞行怎么样?
How was the flight?
好吧。
Okay.
你还好吧?
You doing all right?
-我很好。——好。
- I'm okay, yeah. - Good.
好。你有衣服要洗吗?
Good. You got some laundry for me?
是的。一些。
Yeah. Some.
我会完成的。
I'll get it done.
他们多给了我们两天探监时间。
They gave us two more visiting days.
下一班是周五下午两点。
The next one's, uh, Friday, 2:00 p.m.
克怎么样?
How's Gram?
她很好。
She's good.
氧气罐还在。
Still got the oxygen tank.
还是有很多意见。
Still got plenty of opinions.
想念她。
Miss her.
她给你买了你想要的一切。
She bought you everything you wanted.
我们给你多买了一双袜子还有一双很好的新运动鞋。
Uh, we got you a extra pair of socks and, uh, good new pair of sneakers.
谢谢。
Thanks.
奶奶说她要给你一些照片给我。
Uh, Gram said that she was giving you some photos for me.
啊,狗屎。我忘记他们。
Ah, shit. I forgot them.
哦，下次带就行了。
Oh, just bring them next time.
不，我是说我把它们忘在斯蒂尔沃特的家里了。
No, I mean I forgot them at home in Stillwater.
对不起。
Sorry.
没关系。
Doesn't matter.
我在机场给你买了件牛仔运动衫。
I got you, uh, a Cowboys sweatshirt at the airport.
今年会很不错的。
They're gonna be good this year.
他们从格思里那里得到了一个大边锋。
They got this big ol' tight end out of Guthrie.
大概三个人就能搞定他。
Takes about three guys to bring him down.
他肯定会成为职业选手。
He gonna go pro for sure.
酷。
Cool.
你还在图书馆工作吗?
You still working at the library?
不,我辞职了。
No, I quit.
爸爸，我需要你做点什么。
Um, Dad, I need you to do something.
我要你把它带给勒帕克，确保她能读到。
I need you to get that to Leparq, make sure she reads it.
——好吗?-这是什么?
- Okay? - Wh-What is it?
这是一封信。给她就行了。
It's-it's a letter. Just give it to her.
-是的,是的。-地址在信封上，好吗?
- Yeah, yeah. - The-the address is on the envelope, okay?
是的,好的。
Yeah, okay.
但你还好吗?
But are you good?
爸爸,请。
Dad, please.
我今天就去做。
I'll do it today.
我会确保她读到的。
I'll make sure she reads it.
好吧。
Okay.
介意我们祈祷一下吗?
Mind if we pray a bit?
是的,当然,爸爸。
Yeah, sure, Dad.
主啊，感谢你让我们在这美好的日子相聚感谢你一直关注着艾莉森。
Thank you, Lord, for bringing us together on this blessed day and thank you for keeping a watchful eye on Allison.
贝克先生。
Mr. Baker.
很抱歉让你久等了，Maitre Leparq今天不回办公室了。
I'm sorry you had to wait, but Maitre Leparq is not coming back to the office today.
那我明天再来。谢谢你,女士。
I'll come back tomorrow, then. Thank you, ma'am.
贝克先生，她这周都在法庭上。
Mr. Baker, she's in court all week.
为什么不把你的信给我，我会确保她收到的。
Why don't you give me your letter and I will make sure she gets it.
不能那么做。谢谢你,女士。
Can't do that. Thank you, ma'am.
如你所愿。
As you wish.
-你好。-嗨。
- Bonjour. - Hey.
你被锁在外面了?
You locked out?
什么?
Quoi?
钥匙。你有钥匙吗?
Key. You got a key?
啊,恩,没有。
Ah, euh, non.
来吧，我们去拿。
Come on, let's go get it.
来吧。我去给你弄把新钥匙。
Come on. I'm gonna get you a new key.
贝尔?
Bell?
比尔。
Bill.
比尔?
Beal?
近了。
Closer.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
——嗯?——你。
- Hmm? - You.
玛雅。
Maya.
玛雅。啊,那很好啊。
Maya. Ah, that's nice.
这是什么?
C'est quoi?
这是一个纹身。
It's a tattoo.
嗯?
Hmm?
哦，是一只鹰。
Oh, it's a eagle.
——鹰?- - - - - -鹰。
- Eagle? - Eagle.
秃鹰。美国。
Bald eagle. America.
是啊，我的头骨上还插着刀。
Yeah, and I got a skull with a knife going through it.
——谢谢。-谢谢，女士。
- Merci. - Thank you, ma'am.
谢谢。
Merci.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
下午。我在找那个人Maitre Leparq。
Afternoon. I'm looking for, uh, for that person, Maitre Leparq.
Leparq女士吗?
Ms. Leparq?
贝克先生?——是的,女士。
- Mr. Baker? - Yes, ma'am.
我只是想占用你几分钟时间。
I just need a few minutes of your time.
我女儿的信。
Letter from my daughter.
很抱歉，贝克先生，但我不能满足您女儿的要求。
I'm sorry, Mr. Baker, but I cannot honor your daughter's request.
为什么?
Why's that?
贝克先生，法官不会根据传闻重新审理此案。
Mr. Baker, a judge will not reopen this case based on hearsay.
这不可能。
This is not possible.
好吧。
Okay.
我们已经用尽了所有可能的法律手段。
We have exhausted every possible legal action.
这封信告诉我，你女儿还没有接受她的判决。
This letter tells me that your daughter has not accepted her sentence.
她必须。
And she must.
你明白吗?
Do you understand?
是的,女士。
Yes, ma'am.
我必须走了。
I must go.
我今天很忙。
I have a full day.
我能拿回那封信吗?
Can I get that letter back?
如你所愿。
As you wish.
——谢谢。-贝克先生，有时需要希望，有时需要接受。
- Thank you. - Mr. Baker, there's a time for hope and there's a time for acceptance.
你最不想给你女儿的就是虚假的希望。
The last thing you want to give your daughter is false hope.
这可能会让她的处境非常糟糕。
That could make her situation very dire.
你明白吗?
Do you understand?
是的,女士。
Yes, ma'am.
你好。
Hello.
嘿。
Hey.
谢谢你昨天帮了我女儿玛雅。
Uh, thank you for helping my daughter Maya yesterday.
我回来晚了一点。
I was a little bit late coming back.
你知道的，我们现在住在两套公寓之间，而且我们的新家没有电。
It's, uh, you know, we're between apartments, and we don't have electricity at our new place.
对不起,我……我不会说英语。
So... Sorry, I... I don't speak English.
哦,是的。
Oh, yes.
阳台上。是的。
The balcony. Yeah.
我的英语能力恢复了。
Um, well, my-my English came back to me.
很抱歉声音太大了。
Uh, I'm-I'm sorry for the loud noise.
那是因为我的女朋友奈杰玛。
It's because of my girlfriend Nedjma.
她对我有不好的影响。
She's a bad influence on me.
我,呃,小薇吉妮。
I'm, uh, Virginie.
我是比尔。
I'm Bill.
你好,比尔。
Hello, Bill.
你来马赛度假?
You're in Marseille for vacation?
去看我女儿。
Uh, visiting my daughter.
它很酷。
It's cool.
希望我们只在这里多待一两天，但如果你有什么需要，我们就在隔壁。
Well, hopefully we're only here for one or two more days, but if you need anything, you know, we're next door.
谢谢你,女士。
Thank you, ma'am.
谢谢你！再见,比尔。
Thank you. Bye, Bill.
"亲爱的Maitre Leparq "我给你写信是因为"帕特里克·奥科内多博士"联系了我，他是我大学时参与的外展项目的负责人。
"Dear Maitre Leparq, "I'm writing to you because I was contacted by "Dr. Patrick Okonedo, "uh, chief of the outreach program "I was involved in at university.
帕特里克遇到了一个学生他在派对上遇到了一个叫阿基姆的人。
"Patrick was approached by a student "who met a guy named Akim at a party.
"她被告知他多年前刺伤了一个女孩"然后逃脱了。
"She was told he had stabbed a girl years ago "and got away with it.
肯定是那个杀了莉娜的阿基姆"
It must be the same Akim who killed Lina."
你是那个美国学生的父亲吗?
You're the father of the girl, the-the American student?
是的,女士。
Yes, ma'am.
嗯…必须将他的DNA与犯罪现场发现的未知DNA进行比对。
Um... "H-His DNA must be compared "to the unknown DNA found on the crime scene.
"我，我请求你去调查一下"去和Okonedo先生和那个学生谈谈。
"I, uh, I beg you to investigate, "to talk to Mr. Okonedo and to the student.
"我是无辜的"而且没有其他人来协助我。
"I am innocent of this crime, "and I have no one else to assist me.
"我祖母再也不能去马赛了"你认识我父亲。
"My grandmother can no longer make the trips to Marseille, "and you know my father.
“这件事我不能交给他。
"I cannot trust him with this.
“他没有能力。
"He's not capable.
“请不要把我丢在这个可怕的地方。
"Please do not abandon me in this horrible place.
"我失去了生命中的五年"我还剩四年。
"I have lost five years of my life, "and I still have four to go.
真诚,艾莉森贝克。”
Sincerely, Allison Baker."
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
感谢你的帮助。
Appreciate your help.
请不要把这件事告诉任何人。
Please don't say anything to anybody about this.
是的,当然可以。
Oui, bien sur.
贝克先生。拜托,这里。
Mr. Baker. Please, this way.
我能帮你什么吗?
So, how can I help you?
我想见Leparq夫人谈谈案子的事。
Well, I want to see Mrs. Leparq about the case.
Maitre Leparq今天无法访问。
Maitre Leparq is not available today.
有新线索了。
There's a new lead.
这家伙……在一个派对上谈论谋杀案。
This guy... was talking at a party about the murder.
-贝克先生…-需要有人跟这位老师谈谈，帕特里克·奥科内多。
- Mr. Baker... - So somebody needs to talk to this teacher, this guy, Patrick Okonedo.
我们得听听他想说什么。
We need to hear what he has to say.
贝克先生，Maitre Leparq昨天跟你说得很清楚了。
Mr. Baker, Maitre Leparq was very clear with you yesterday.
她不能继续追查这个案子。
She cannot pursue this case.
但如果你想做进一步的调查，我们可以建议你这么做。
But if you wish to pursue a further investigation, we can recommend this.
这是一份你可以聘用的私家侦探名单。
It's a list of private detectives you can engage.
不，我不要，我不要侦探。
No, I don't want, I don't want a detective.
我们和这个名单上的人合作过，他们都很能干。
We have worked with the people on this list, and they're all very capable.
我不在乎他们有多能干。我不希望…-我在圈名字，你可以…-别兜圈子了。
I don't care how capable they are. I don't want... - I'm circling the names that you can... - Stop circling that.
我女儿在监狱里。
My daughter's in fucking jail.
我不需要什么该死的名单。
I don't need some fucking list.
呃，你还好吧？
Euh, ca va?
是的，是的，我很好，是的。
Oui, oui, ca va, oui.
谢谢。
Merci.
随你的便。
As you want.
去他妈的。
Fuck this.
谢谢,Sybille。
Merci, Sybille.
-嗨。-嗨。
- Hey. Mm. - Hi.
——你好吗?-我很好，我很好
- You good? - Yeah, I'm good, I'm good.
今天让你出去晚一点。他们不应该那样做。
Let you out a bit late today. They shouldn't do that.
你知道他们会准时给你打电话的。
You know they're gonna call you back in on time.
没关系。有时会发生这种事。
It's okay. It happens sometimes.
-我帮你洗衣服了。——谢谢。
- I did your laundry. - Thanks.
你把我的信给勒帕克了吗?
Um, did you give my letter to Leparq?
是的,当然。
Yeah, of course.
她怎么说?
And what'd she say?
她跟我说了你写的关于阿基姆和派对上那个女孩的事。-她怎么说?
Well, uh, she told me what you wrote about Akim - and the girl at the party. - And what'd she say?
她说，你知道，她处理过很多这样的案子……爸爸。
Well, she said, you know, she works on a lot of these cases... Dad.
她到底要不要调查?
Is she gonna investigate it or not?
告诉我。
Just tell me.
是的，她会调查的。
Yeah, she's gonna look into it.
真的吗?
Really?
她说的?
She said that?
她说她会调查的?
She said she's gonna look into it?
这是正确的。
That's right.
我告诉她你有多强烈。
I told her how strongly you felt about it.
她需要我做什么吗?
Does she need me to do anything?
不。她说她只是需要点时间，还有…她确实说过，她不想做任何承诺。
No. She said she just needs some time, and, uh... She did say, uh, she didn't want to make any promises.
她不想给你任何虚假的希望或类似的东西。-不不不不
She-she didn't want to give you any false hope - or nothing like that. - No, no, no, no, no.
但这仍然很棒。
But that's-that's still great.
Akim存在。
Akim exists.
他杀了莉娜。
He killed Lina.
我知道。
I know.
I know that.
你不知道那封信我写了多少遍又重写了多少遍。
You have no idea how many times I-I wrote and then rewrote that letter.
哦,我的上帝。
Oh, my God.
嗯，它起作用了。
Well, it worked.
是的。
Yeah.
也许上帝回应了我们的祈祷。
Maybe God answered our prayers.
谢谢你,爸爸。
Thank you, Dad.
非常感谢。
Thank you so much.
对不起,女士。
Excuse me, ma'am.
比尔贝克。我打电话问名单的事。
Bill Baker. Called about a list.
请等一下。
One moment please.
我不知道你对这个案子记得多少，但艾莉森来这里上大学，她就是在那里认识了莉娜。
I don't know how much you remember about the case, but Allison came here for college, and that's where she met this girl, Lina.
艾莉森和莉娜在一起，有天晚上他们大吵了一架，艾莉森去了一家酒吧。
Allison and Lina were... together, and one night they got in a big fight, and Allison went to a bar.
她就是在那里认识了那个叫阿基姆的。
That's where she met this Akim guy.
他们喝了些饮料。
And they had some drinks.
他偷了她的钱包，艾莉森回家后，发现莉娜死了，就报了警。
He stole her purse, and... when Allison got home, she found Lina dead and called the police.
他们一直没能找到这个阿基姆。
And they never could find this Akim.
是他杀了莉娜
He's the one who killed Lina.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm.
你会说英语，对吧?
You speak English, right?
英语吗?
English?
是的。我是。
Yes. I am.
他妈的。
Fuck.
把信还给我。
Give me back the letter.
贝克先生。
Mr. Baker.
请。
Please.
我的办公室。
My office.
这个案子发生的时候我还在服役。
I was in service at the time of this case.
在警察局。
In the police.
你跟这个Okonedo谈过了吗?
Have you talked to this Okonedo?
——教授。——不,先生。
- The professor. - No, sir.
我知道你的律师为什么不想帮忙了。
I see why your lawyer doesn't want to help.
某个孩子在派对上听到了谋杀的流言。
Some kid at a party hears gossip about a murder.
也许她还记得这个著名的案子。
Maybe she remembers this famous case.
为什么是现在?那是五年前的事了。
Why now? It was five years ago.
我儿子在监狱里待了这么久，五年。
That's... that's how long my kid's been in jail, five years.
她知道我们要见面吗?
Does she know we are meeting?
你的孩子。
Your kid.
不,先生。
No, sir.
你有钱吗，贝克先生?
Are you rich, Mr. Baker?
没有,先生。
No, sir.
这是一个DNA案件。
This is a DNA case.
它意味着两个步骤。
It means two steps.
首先，我要找那个年轻人。
First, I look for the young man.
这并不容易。
That will not be easy.
人们会说话。他会试图消失。
People will talk. He will try to disappear.
如果我找到这个阿基姆，我就得拿到他的DNA样本然后利用我在警局的关系把它和犯罪现场的DNA做对比。
Then, if I find this Akim, I have to get a sample of his DNA and use my connections in the police to test it against the DNA from the crime scene.
多少钱?
How much?
12000美元?
$12,000?
欧元。
Euros.
谢谢你抽出时间。
Thank you for your time.
贝克先生。
Mr. Baker.
你相信你女儿是无辜的吗?
Do you believe your daughter is innocent?
我知道她是。
I know she is.
那也许看到她重获自由就不算什么了。
Then maybe it's not so much to see her go free.
-打扰一下，女士。——是吗?
- Excuse me, ma'am. - Yes?
-能问你个问题吗?-当然可以。
- Ask you a question, please? - Yes, of course.
我只是太蠢了，一个人搞不懂。
I'm just too much of a dumbass to figure this out on my own.
我不会说法语。
I don't speak French.
我能帮你什么吗?
Uh, how can I help you?
我在找一个在这里工作的人。
I'm looking for a guy, uh, who works here.
——是吗?-对不起打断一下。
- Oui? - Sorry to interrupt.
你会说英语吗?
Do you speak English?
我会。
I do.
找帕特里克·奥科内多。
Looking for Patrick Okonedo.
请坐。
Have a seat please.
没关系。我就在外面等着。
That's all right. I'll wait outside.
不,不,谢谢。加入派对。
No, no, please. Join the party.
这是令人印象深刻的,是吧?
It's impressive, huh?
这是一间有博士学位的办公室。
It's the kind of office a PhD will get you.
薄荷茶。
Mint tea.
我想和你在派对上跟艾莉森说的那个女孩谈谈。
I want to talk to the girl you told Allison about from the party.
是的。我也这么认为。
Yes. I assumed as much.
说实话，我一直对发生的事感到内疚。
To be honest, I've always felt guilty about what happened.
我应该提醒艾莉森的。
I should've warned Allison.
警告她?关于什么?
Warned her? About what?
我知道艾莉森和莉娜睡在一起，但我不知道莉娜搬去和她住了。
Well, I knew Allison and Lina were sleeping together, but I had no idea Lina had moved in with her.
我尽量不去怀疑这种类型的关系。贫民区的穷女孩，有钱的美国学生…但我却为自己的天真而感到内疚。
I try to not be cynical about these type of relationships... poor girl from the ghetto, rich American student... but then I end up being guilty of naivete.
艾利森出身贫寒。
Allison grew up poor.
她并不富有。
She isn't rich.
有教养的。
Educated.
人们对文化精英有很多不满。
There is a lot of resentments towards the cultural elite.
但我相信你已经意识到了。
But I'm sure you're aware of that.
派对上那个女孩呢?
What about the girl from the party?
——我的学生吗?-是的。
- My student? - Yeah.
她的名字叫Souad。
Her name is Souad.
她是外展项目的，莉娜和艾莉森刚认识的时候也参加了这个项目。
She's from the outreach program, the same one Lina and Allison were involved with when they met.
她听到有人在说莉娜的谋杀案吗?
And she heard some guy talking about Lina's murder?
这是她告诉我的。
This is what she told me.
我能和她说话吗?
Could I talk to her?
她会跟你谈的，是的。
She'll talk to you, yes.
我把她的电话号码给你。
I'll give you her phone number.
苏德英语说得不好。
Souad doesn't speak English very well.
你需要有人来翻译。
You will need someone to translate.
你能帮我吗?
Oh, could you do that for me?
不，我不愿意。
No, I'd rather not.
我还在负责外展项目。
I'm still running the outreach program.
我不能和你在一起。
I cannot be associated with you.
或者你女儿，在发生了那些事之后。
Or your daughter, after what happened.
不管我个人的看法是什么。
Whatever my personal opinion may be.
我的女儿是无辜的。
My daughter's innocent.
祝你好运。
I wish you good luck.
帕特丽夏，恐怕我又需要帮助了。
Hey, Patricia, afraid I need some help again.
我明天要参加一个很特别的生日聚会，我把地址弄丢了。
I'm supposed to attend a very special birthday tomorrow, and I lost the address.
你好吗?
Bonjour?
嗨。比尔•贝克。
Hi. It's Bill Baker.
能再重复一遍吗?
Pardon?
-比尔，从酒店来的——啊,比尔。
- Bill, from the hotel. - Ah, Bill.
是的，我顺路过来。对不起……-最后一层。——好的。
Yeah, I was stopping by. Sorry to... - Uh, last floor. - All right.
嗨,比尔。
Hi, Bill.
嘿,玛雅。
Hey, Maya.
我有东西给你。
I got something for you.
这是一个机器人。
It's a robot.
-嗨。-嗨。对不起,打扰了。
- Hi. - Hi. Sorry to intrude.
不,没关系。进来吧。
No, it's okay. Come in.
我有几个朋友过来。
Um, I have some friends over.
哦。
Oh.
你怎么找到我们的?
How did you find us?
前台的女士给了我你的地址，因为我要给一个女孩打电话，但她不会说英语，这是私事。
Oh, the lady at reception gave me your address 'cause there's this girl I need to call, but she don't speak English, and it's kind of personal.
你想让我帮你打个电话。是这样吗?
Ah, you want me to make the call for you. Is that right?
好的，女士，不过我下次再来。
Yes, ma'am, but I'll come back another time.
不,它很好。刚进来。
No, it's fine. Uh, just come in.
让我拿一下手机。
Just let me grab my phone.
来了。
Come.
嘿。
Hey.
比尔，这是马赛剧院的creme de la crme。
Bill, this is, uh, the creme de la crme of the Marseille theater scene.
是啊。
Ouais.
我们在做一个，面具练习。
Uh, we're doing this, uh, mask exercise.
——好的。-是的。
- All right. - Yeah.
屋子很乱,请原谅。
Excuse the mess.
这将是我的办公室，但我们还是要搬进去。
This is going to be my office, but we're still moving in.
请坐。
Have a seat.
我要打给谁?
So, who am I calling?
嗯…信上的那个女孩。
Um... the girl from the letter.
-是关于案子的吗?——是的,女士。
- Ah, it's about the case? - Yes, ma'am.
我想见见她。
I want to meet with her.
律师没有帮你吗?
Is the lawyer not helping you?
呃，现在我自己来。
Uh, doing it myself for now.
哦。哇。
Oh. Wow.
好吧。嗯…
Okay. Um...
——是的。——嗯…
- Oui. - Um...
多划算啊，我通过我的一个朋友买下了这个地方。
What a great deal, I got this place through this friend of mine.
我很喜欢这里的景色，但有一些缺点。
I fell in love with this view, but, uh, has a few defects.
可能只是一个断路器。
Probably just a circuit breaker.
如果你想的话，我可以帮你看看。
I could look at it if you want.
-是的。你知道怎么做吗?——是的,女士。
- Yeah. You know how to do that? - Yes, ma'am.
那太好了。
Well, that would be great.
Souad?Souad?
Souad? Souad?
是的,你好。Souad?
Oui, bonjour. Souad?
你好。
Bonjour.
．..比尔贝克。
...Bill Baker.
比尔•贝克……哦,不。
Bill Baker... Oh, non.
让我看看。让我看看。
Let me see. Let me see.
-♪你好♪-酷。
- ♪ Hey ♪ - Cool.
♪性感的夫人……♪
♪ Sexy lady... ♪
我不知道它会这样。
I didn't know it did that.
这很容易。等一等。那就这样吧。
That-that goes on easy. Hold on. There you go.
看起来不错。
Looks good.
非常感谢。
Merci beaucoup.
再见。
Au revoir.
好吧。她同意明天6点见你。
Okay. She agrees to see you tomorrow at 6:00.
好吧。
All right.
她人很好。
Um, she was nice.
有点害羞。
Bit shy.
如果你不讲法语，你要怎么跟她说话?
So how are you gonna talk to her if you don't speak French?
这个问题问得很好。
Well, that's a fair question.
我会想办法的。
I'll figure it out.
好吧。
Okay.
如果你需要，我可以过来翻译。
Well, I could come and translate if you need.
你确定吗?
You sure?
嗯,是的。
Uh, yeah.
玛雅有美术课，如果你五点半来，我们就开我的车。
Yeah, Maya has art class, so if you come here at 5:30, then we take my car.
谢谢。
Appreciate it.
你告诉我保险丝盒在哪里，我帮你修理断路器。
Uh, you show me where that fuse box is, I'll work on that breaker for you.
不,这是好的。
No, it's okay.
你没必要这么做。
You don't have to do that.
哦,不,不。
Oh, non, non.
把那该死的东西给我。我…来吧。
Just give me that damn thing. I... Come on.
比尔!
Bill!
再见,比尔!
Bye, Bill!
再见。
Bye.
我得承认，我上网看了艾莉森的案子。
I have to confess, uh, I went online and I read about Allison's case.
这在当时是个大新闻。
It was a big story at the time.
我是说，媒体很凶，不是吗?
I mean, the-the press was ferocious, no?
你说“f-ferocious”?
Y-You say "f-ferocious"?
-是的，女士，我们是这么说的——是吗?
- Yes, ma'am, we say that. - Yeah?
莆田市。
Putain.
笨蛋。
Dumbass.
是的,…这里的人都不知道怎么开车。
Yeah, people... they don't know how to drive in this fucking town.
马赛是个疯狂的地方。
It's a crazy place, Marseille.
但比起巴黎，我还是更喜欢巴黎。
But I still prefer it to Paris.
你知道吗，这里的人会互相交谈。
You know, people actually talk to each other here.
而且，它更便宜。
And plus, it's cheaper.
艾利森为什么来这里上学?
And why did Allison come here for school?
我很好奇。
I'm curious.
——不知道。——不是吗?
- Don't know. - No?
是的，她要去俄克拉荷马州立大学。
Yeah, she was going to Oklahoma State.
有一天她打电话给我，说"我要去法国"去这里。
She just called me up one day, said, "I'm going to France," to here.
她是独立的。
She's independent.
是的,女士。总是。
Yes, ma'am. Always been.
你关闭吗?
Are you close?
你读了她的信。
Well, you read her letter.
她妈妈在哪儿?
And where is her mother?
她通过了。
She passed.
她自杀了。
Killed herself.
艾莉森主要是由她奶奶养大的。
Allison was raised by her grandmother mostly.
我不常在你身边。
I wasn't around much.
你在哪里?
Where were you?
在石油钻塔上工作，当我不是的时候却一团糟。
Working oil rigs and... being a fuckup when I wasn't.
做一个单亲妈妈并不容易。
It's not easy being a single parent.
我经常在晚上工作，而玛雅，她很沮丧。
I often work at night, and Maya, she gets really upset.
-你是做什么的?-我是个演员。
- What do you do? - I'm an actress.
-在电视上?——没有。
- Oh, on TV? - No.
剧院。
Theater.
你去剧院吗?
Do you go to theater?
不,女士。
No, ma'am.
——从来没有?——不,女士。
- Never? - No, ma'am.
好吧。
Okay.
谢谢你们跟我聊天。
Uh, thank y'all for talking to me.
她在派对上认识的那个人，阿基姆关于他，她有什么线索吗?
So, this guy that she met at the party, Akim... uh, anything she could tell us about him?
她说他很安静，人也很好。
She said he was quiet and nice.
好吗?
Nice?
然后他告诉她的朋友他刺伤了一个女孩警察一直没抓到他。
And then he told her friend he'd stabbed a girl and that the police never caught him.
——所以……——好的。
- So... - Okay.
她知道他住哪儿吗?
Does she know where he lives?
——Kalliste。——Kalliste ?
- a Kalliste. - Kalliste?
她说他住在另一个项目里。
She says he lives in a different project.
它叫做Kalliste。
It's called Kalliste.
-她在说什么?——没有什么帮助。
- What's she saying? - Nothing helpful.
我,嗯…父亲。
I-I'm, uh... le pere.
哦,埃里森。
Uh, Allison.
那是我的小女儿。
That's my little girl.
艾利森是我的妈妈。
Allison is my... ma fille.
你明白吗?
You understand?
她不想帮忙。
She doesn't want to help.
她能告诉我什么吗?
Can she tell me anything?
这家伙长什么样子?
Wh-What does this guy look like?
-他们要去哪里?——他们要离开。
- Where they going? - They're leaving.
不，不，不。等一下，等一下，等一下。
Uh, no, no, no. Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
等等,不,不。等一等。只是等待。不,不。
Wait, no, no. Hold on. Just wait. No, no.
-好吧，好吧-哇，哇，哇!Wouah !
- All right, all right. - Wouah, wouah, wouah! Wouah!
Souad。嘿,Souad !Souad !
Souad. Hey, Souad! Souad!
比尔，比尔，让他们走，好吗?她的害怕。
Bill, Bill, let them go, okay? She's afraid.
害怕什么?我在跟她说话。
Afraid of what? I'm talking to her.
是啊，但这里不是这样的。
Yeah, but that's not how it works here.
那你告诉我是怎么回事，因为这里没人帮我。
Well, you tell me how it works then, 'cause nobody here's doing shit for me.
我什么都为你做，好吗?
I do shit for you, okay?
我们应该去。现在。
We should go. Now.
好吧?
Okay?
-好吧——好吧?
- Yeah, all right. - All right?
就是这样。Kalliste。
That's it. Kalliste.
她说阿基姆住在那里。
That's where she says Akim lives.
我们可以四处看看吗?
Well, can we go look around?
不。现在不行。
No. Not at this time.
对我们来说不安全。
It's not safe for us.
因为我们是白色?
'Cause we're white?
因为我们不是那里的人。
'Cause we're not from there.
有很多交易。
And there's a lot of dealing.
我得做点什么。
Well, I got to do something.
没人会跟你说话的，相信我。
No one will talk to you, trust me.
比尔，如果没有阿基姆呢?
Bill, what if there's no Akim?
有。
There is.
好吧，但他们在调查过程中没找到这个人。
Okay, but they never found this person during the investigation.
我女儿不是骗子。
My daughter's not a liar.
不，我没说她是。
No, I didn't say she was.
只是我读到的所有关于这个案子的资料…你现在算是专家了吗?
It's just that everything I read about the case... So you're some kind of expert now?
不,我不是。
No, I'm not.
新闻界反对我们。
The press was against us.
他们只关心艾莉森和某个阿拉伯女孩上床。
All they cared about was Allison was sleeping with some Arab girl.
一群假新闻的人渣。
Bunch of... fake news scumbags.
所以你才打了那个英国记者?
That's why you punched that English reporter?
我当时正在喝酒。
I was drinking then.
你告诉奶奶莱帕克的事了吗?
Hey, did you tell Gram about Leparq?
不。
No.
不，我不想在我们了解更多之前让她抱太大希望。
No, I didn't want to get her hopes up until we know more.
你奶奶，她上年纪了。
She's getting on, your grandmother.
我昨天和法官见了面。
Oh, I had a meeting with the judge yesterday.
噢,是吗?关于什么?
Oh, yeah? About what?
我三个月后就要假释审查了。
Well, I have my parole review coming up in about three months.
这就是我一个月有一天能离开这里的原因。
And, uh, it's the thing where I get out of here one day a month.
是的,好的。
Yeah, okay.
-他怎么说?——她。她说。
- So what'd he say? - She. She said.
你知道，只要我表现良好，就不会有问题。
Uh, you know, as long as my behavior remained good, shouldn't be a problem.
我想说，去他的假释。
I felt like saying, "Fuck parole.
我的律师正在想办法让我永远离开这里"
My lawyer's working on getting me out of here for good."
不，我们还不知道，艾丽。
No, we don't know that yet, Ally.
-你得继续…-我知道，我知道，爸爸。
- You got to keep... - I know, I know, I know, Dad.
我没那么说。但我想这么做。
I-I didn't say that. But I wanted to.
Leparq办公室的人也在那里。
And... somebody from Leparq's office was there.
噢,是吗?
Oh, yeah?
是的。我没见过她，但我问她调查进展如何。
Yeah. I never met her, but I asked her how the investigation was going.
她跟你说什么了?
What'd she tell you?
她说她什么都不知道，但她还说她刚开始在那里工作。
She said she didn't know anything about it, but she also said she just started working there.
勒帕克可能会自己处理。
Leparq's probably taking care of it herself.
这是个大案子。
It's a big case.
是的。
Yeah.
我告诉她我想和莱帕克谈谈。
I told her I wanted to talk to Leparq.
她应该随时通知我们。
She should be keeping us informed.
-你懂我的意思吗?-我会跟她说的
- You know what I mean? - I'll talk to her.
好吧。嗯…过几天见。
Okay. Well... I'll see you in a couple days.
爸，你能不能在马赛多待一会儿?
Uh, Dad, do you think that you could stay in Marseille a little longer?
以防万一。
Just in case something comes up.
是的，我可以。
Yeah, I could do that.
我去检查一下工作情况。
I'll check in on work and stuff.
如果你需要的话，我可以让奶奶给你电汇钱。
I-I can have Gram wire you some money if you need.
不，不，别这样。我会想办法的。
No, no, don't do that. I-I'll figure it out.
谢谢,爸爸。
Thanks, Dad.
再见。
Bye.
嗯,马克斯。
Uh, Max.
你好。
Salut.
——协议。——嗯。
- D'accord. - Ay.
现在，一旦石油公司有了租约…给我，M。
Now, once the oil company has a lease... Give it here, M.
来吧。
Come on.
一旦石油公司拿到租约，他们就会雇佣一家钻井公司。
Once that oil company has that lease, they hire a drilling company.
我就是为他工作的
That's who I work for.
然后我们到了那里，把所有的东西组装起来。
And then we get there, we rig up and we put all that shit together.
一旦装备好了，我们就开始挖洞。
Once we have that rig up, we start making hole.
这就是钻工的工作。
That's what a roughneck does.
我们打洞。
We make hole.
好吧，测试一下。
All right, test it.
继续冲吧
Go on, flush it.
得到它。
Get it.
——冲洗。——啊,冲洗。
- Flush. - Ah, flush.
-是的。——是吧。
- Yeah. - D'accord.
冲洗。
Flush.
- Ca va ?-当然了，ca va!
- Ca va? - Hell yeah, ca va!
比尔,来了。
Bill, come.
到这里来。
Come here.
过来看看这个。
Come and see this.
Nedjma是一个技术天才。
Nedjma is a technical genius.
我不是天才。我只是年轻。
I'm not a genius. I'm just younger.
-好吧…-这些是网上的吗?
- Okay... - These are online or some shit?
这些都是Souad和她那个贱朋友的Instagram账号。
These are all from Instagram accounts of Souad and her bitchy friend.
这些照片都是派对上拍的。
And these photos are all from the party.
你们怎么拿到的?
How'd y'all get them?
我注册了一个虚假的Instagram账号，跟踪了苏德和她可爱的朋友萨米拉，然后定位了苏德看到这家伙时参加的派对。
I set up a false Instagram account, followed Souad and her lovely friend whose name is Samira, and then geotagged the party Souad was at when she saw this guy.
所以阿基姆有可能在其中一张照片里。
So there's a chance Akim is in one of these photos.
．..阿拉伯人，皮肤白皙。
...Arab and light skin.
是啊，肤色浅，个子高。
Yeah, uh, light skin, yeah, and tall.
我们要把它们打印出来，然后你可以拿给艾莉森看。
So we're going to print them up, and then you can show them to Allison.
-不，我不会那么做的。——为什么?
- No, I'm not gonna do that. - Why?
如果阿基姆在那里，她会知道的。
If Akim is there, she'll know.
我也不在乎
I don't care.
我不会那么做的。我不会这么对她的。
I'm not gonna do that. I'm not gonna do it to her.
我得保护她。
I got to protect her.
我不明白你的意思。
I don't understand.
你为什么对艾莉森这么固执?
Wh-why you're being so stubborn about Allison?
我们现在要做的是回到苏阿德我们拿到了那些照片。
What we should do is go back to Souad now we got those pictures.
我们从Instagram上偷了这些照片，所以我不确定这是不是个好主意。
Well, we stole these photos from Instagram, so I'm not sure this is a good idea.
——嗯…-我能说句话吗?
- Well... - Can I say something?
是啊,说吧。
Ouais, vas-y.
马赛有其他人见过阿基姆还是只有艾莉森?
Did anyone else in Marseille see this Akim guy or just Allison?
酒吧老板。
Bar owner.
他们相遇的地方。
Where they met.
他在审判现场。
He was at the trial.
-他什么都没做，但是…——好的。
- He didn't do shit, but... - Okay.
那个酒吧叫什么来着?的叫什么名字?
Uh, what's it called, the bar? What's the name?
我不记得名字了。
I don't remember the name of it.
-就在她公寓附近-是的。好吧。
- It was near her apartment. - Yeah. Okay.
-嗯-嗯
- Mm. - Mm.
好吧。
Okay.
比尔，你投票给特朗普了吗?
Bill, did you vote for Trump?
不。
No.
啊。瞧。
Ah. Voila.
-我没有投票。——什么?
- I didn't vote. - What?
-你为什么不投票?-有案底。
- Why didn't you vote? - Got a record.
我被逮捕。
I was arrested.
这种情况下他们不让你投票。
They don't let you vote when that happens.
就在那儿，就在那个角落。
It's there, around that corner.
你的朋友，奈杰玛…她因为你帮了我而生气吗?
Your friend, uh, Nedjma... she mad at you for helping me?
不要担心Nedjma;她通常怀有敌意。
Don't worry about Nedjma; she's generally hostile.
她对我保护欲很强，但她是我的好朋友。
You know, she's very protective with me, but she's a good friend.
她帮我照顾玛雅。
She helps me with Maya.
玛雅的父亲在哪儿?
Where's Maya's father?
科西嘉岛，在海滩上开夜总会。
Corsica, running a nightclub on the beach.
他是个放荡的人。
He was a... a fling.
-你是这么说的?——扔,是的。
- That's how you say? - Fling, yeah.
是的。
Yeah.
他访问吗?
Does he visit?
他以前喜欢，但他不喜欢的时候更好。
He used to, but it's better when he doesn't.
什么?
What?
那是艾莉森住的地方。
That's where Allison lived.
21岁。
Twenty-one.
就是在那里发生的吗?
That's where it happened?
是的。
Yeah.
-你好。-你好。
- Bonjour. - Bonjour.
他是新老板。
He's the new owner.
案发时他不在现场。
He wasn't there when the crime happened.
他知道我们在哪能找到原来的主人吗?
Does he know where we could find the old owner?
是的,我知道。
Yes, I know.
他是对的。
He's right there.
喝我的利润。
Drinking my profits.
Euhm……
Euhm...
他承认任何人吗?
He recognize anybody?
他说了什么?
What's he saying?
莆田市。
Putain.
好吧。生活就是好。我们走吧。
Okay. C'est bon. Let's go.
他说什么?
What'd he say?
什么都没有。他是无用的。
Nothing. He's useless.
嘿。
Hey.
嘿!
Hey!
嘿!发生了什么事?
Hey! What happened?
我很抱歉。我只是…我不能再和那家伙说话了。
I'm sorry. I just, uh... I can't talk to that guy anymore.
他只是说了一些可怕的事情。
He was just saying some horrible things.
像什么?
Like what?
就好像他只是想把一个阿拉伯小孩送进监狱?
Like he just wants to put an Arab kid in jail, you know?
他不在乎哪一个。
He doesn't care which one.
就这些吗?
That's it?
就这些吗?你说"就这样"是什么意思?
That's it? What do you mean, "That's it"?
他是一个种族主义者。
He's a racist.
好吧，他是个种族主义者。
Okay, he's a racist.
我们还是得和他谈谈。
We still got to talk to him.
不。我不跟他说话，不
No. I don't talk to him, no.
他可能知道些什么。
Well, he might know something.
不，他什么都不知道!
No, he doesn't know something!
比尔，我们不能把一个无辜的孩子送进监狱。
Bill, we're not gonna send an innocent boy to jail.
我女儿是无辜的。
My daughter is innocent.
什么?哦,莆田市。真不敢相信这段对话。
Quoi? Oh, putain. Can't believe this conversation.
那你就活在幻想的世界里了，亲爱的，因为我总是和那种人一起工作。
Well, then y-you live in some fancy-ass world, honey, 'cause I work with guys like that all the time.
不，但没关系，好吗?它是不正确的。
No, but it doesn't matter, okay? It's not right.
我不是说这是…我想把我的女儿从监狱里救出来。
I'm not saying it's ri... I'm trying to get my little girl out of jail.
我他妈只在乎这个。
That's all I give a fuck about.
你现在听起来很像美国人。
And you sound very American right now.
好。我是。
Good. I am.
是啊，你也是个陌生人。
Yeah, and you're also a stranger here.
你什么都不懂。你知道吗?
You don't understand shit. You know what?
贝克先生，请稍等。
Mr. Baker, one moment please.
你有话要说。
You have a message.
她说你需要更多钱因为勒帕克重开了这个案子?
She said you need more money because Leparq reopened the case?
我正在处理，莎伦。
I'm dealing with it, Sharon.
-处理什么?——什么都没有。
- Dealing with what? - Nothing.
艾莉森让我给她一封信。
I mean, Allison told me to give her a letter.
是的，现在勒帕克正在调查。
I did, and now Leparq's looking into it.
她又在找阿基姆了吗?
Well, i-is she looking for Akim again?
我——我……我说了我会处理的，莎伦。
I'm-I'm... I told you I'm dealing with it, Sharon.
-谁来买单?-没人在谈钱。
- Who is gonna pay for this? - Nobody's talking about money.
好吧?
Okay?
比尔，你喝酒了吗?
Bill, have you been drinking?
不。
No.
听着，莎伦，我是她父亲。
Listen, Sharon, I'm her father.
天啊，比尔。
Oh, my God, Bill.
你应该来拜访然后回家。
You're supposed to visit and come home.
别搞砸了。
Don't mess with this.
这事你得相信我。
Y-You're gonna need to trust me on this.
就是这样。
That's it.
我要打电话给Leparq。
I'm gonna call Leparq.
不，别这样，莎伦。
No, don't do that, Sharon.
沙龙!
Sharon!
爸爸，怎么了?
Dad, what is going on?
我跟奶奶谈过了，她说你表现得很奇怪。
I talked to Gram, she said that you're acting really weird.
好吧，我只需要你相信我，好吗?
All right, I just need you to trust me, all right?
我需要你看看这些照片。
I need you to look at these pictures.
爸爸?
Dad?
爸爸……你喝的是什么呢?
Dad... are you drinking?
什么?不,从来没有。
What? No, never.
你使用吗?
Are you using?
艾丽，我受够了。你知道的。
Ally, I'm done with that shit. You know that.
来吧，看看这些照片。
Now, come on, look at these pictures.
这他妈是什么?!Leparq在哪里? !
Wh-What the fuck are these?! Where's Leparq?!
-为什么她没来?!-看看照片，看到Akim就告诉我!
- Wh-Why isn't she here?! - Just look at the photos and tell me if you see Akim!
我想他在里面。
I think he's in there.
请,宝贝。
Please, baby.
请。
Please.
-不，我没看到他。-好吧。有更多的。
- No, I don't see him. - Okay, all right. There's more.
有更多的。
There's more.
天呐
Holy shit.
你看到他了吗?哪一个?
You see him? Which one?
这是他。
That's him.
这是他。这是Akim。
That's him. That's Akim.
你确定吗?就是那晚的那个人吗?
You're sure? That's the guy from that night?
爸爸,就是他。
Daddy, that's him.
Kalliste吗?
Kalliste?
是的。嗯,是的。在那里。
Yeah. Uh, oui. In there.
只管开进去。
Just drive on in.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
对不起,女士。
Excuse me, ma'am.
女士，你以前见过那个人吗?
Ma'am, you seen that guy before?
Akim吗?
Akim?
——不。非。-他住在这里。没有?
- Non. Non. - He lives, he lives here. No?
女士，你以前见过他吗?Akim吗?
Ma'am, have you seen him before? Akim?
对不起,先生。
Excuse me, sir.
-你以前见过那个人吗?——不。
- You seen that guy before? - Non.
你呢?你以前见过这个人吗?
How about you? Have you seen this guy before?
南。
Nan.
-在找他。Akim。——没有。
- Looking for him. Akim. - No.
你认识他吗?Akim吗?
You know him? Akim?
非。
Non.
原谅我。
Excuse me.
你们都认识这家伙?
Y'all know this guy?
他?Akim?
Him? Akim?
非……
Non...
你见过那个人吗?
You ever seen that guy?
Akim吗?
Akim?
不,不。不,不,不。
Non, non. Non, non, non.
这家伙吗?
This guy?
没有?
No?
嘿。你认识那个人吗?
Hey. You know that guy?
在这里吗?Akim吗?
Right there? Akim?
你认识他吗?
You know him?
这个人，阿基姆，他住在这里?
This guy, Akim, he lives here?
是的。
Yeah.
不,不。
Non, non.
Akim怎么样?
How about... Akim?
不,不。
Non, non.
再见,牛仔。
Bye-bye, cowboy.
你会说英语吗?
You speak English?
嘿，你认识这个人吗?这个…他的名字叫Akim。
Hey, you know this guy? This... His name's Akim.
他住在这里。
He li... he lives here.
Akim吗?
Akim?
这家伙住在这里。
The guy lives here.
我说英语。你给我口交。
I-I speak English. You suck my dick.
来吧!
Allez!
——Ici。——谢谢。
- Ici. - Merci.
嗨。
Hi.
他们问我是否认识什么人。
They asked me if I knew anybody.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
我看见他。
I saw him.
我看见Akim。
I saw Akim.
在Kalliste。
In Kalliste.
你告诉警察了吗?
Did you tell the police?
这是我的机会。
That was my chance.
你他妈做了什么?
What the fuck did you do?
我只是想帮忙。
I was trying to help.
告诉我你到底做了什么，爸爸。
Tell me exactly what you did, Dad.
爸爸。
Dad.
她不会这么做的，艾丽。
She wouldn't do it, Ally.
Leparq不愿调查这个案子。
Leparq wouldn't look into the case.
哦,我的上帝。
Oh, my God.
你他妈的说谎了。
You fucking lied.
关于这一切。
About all of it.
当然了。
Of course you did.
我找到他了，艾丽。
I found him, Ally.
我发现Akim。
I found Akim.
你为什么不报警?
And why didn't you call the police?
为什么? !
Why?!
你让他跑了!
You let him get away!
他走了!
He's fucking gone now!
他是他妈的不见了!
He's fucking gone!
我觉得自己好蠢。我觉得自己好蠢。
I feel so stupid. I feel so stupid.
你一直都在骗我，一直都是!
You've always lied to me, my entire life, always!
我恨自己竟然相信你!
I hate myself for ever trusting you!
-艾莉，听我说。——不!
- Ally, listen to me. - No!
不!不。
No! No.
你别再搞砸我的生活了。
You are done fucking up my life.
你明白吗?
Do you get that?
你呢?
Do you?
离我远点。
Stay the fuck away from me.
比尔!比尔!
Bill! Bill!
比尔。
Bill.
嘿,家伙。
Hey, guys.
他,比尔。
He, Bill.
是的，我知道了。
Yeah, I got it.
♬不要担心汽油
♪ Don't worry about gasoline ♪
因为我们要搬家
♪ 'Cause we're moving ♪
♬不要担心电视屏幕♬
♪ Don't worry about the TV screen ♪
♪因为我们要搬家了…♪
♪ 'Cause we're moving... ♪
♬我是♬的浪子
♪ I am the prodigal son ♪
♬我回家就像一把上了膛的枪
♪ I come home just like a loaded gun ♪
♬当我埋在地下六英尺时，我会找到休息的地方……♪
♪ I'll find rest when I'm six feet underground... ♪
——他,比尔。-怎么样?
- He, Bill. - How we doing?
今天在学校过得怎么样?好吗?
How was school today? Good?
你搞定了吗?
You get it done?
好吧，来吧。我们走吧。
All right, come on. Let's go.
是的，我知道了。
Yeah, I got it.
在这里。我给你买的。
Here. I got you that.
玛雅，你得把它全吃了。
Maya, you got to eat the whole thing.
我知道你在做什么，但你也得吃面包。
I see what you're doing, but you got to eat the bread part, too.
你要把它推给我吗?
Oh, you gonna pawn it off on me?
好吧。
All right.
比尔。
Bill.
嗯…锤子。
Uh... un marteau.
是的，先生。好吧，好吧。锤子。
Oui. Tres bien. Marteau.
——锤。——锤。
- Hammer. - Hammer.
嗯…ciseau……嗯…ciseau什么的。
Uh... ciseau... Uh... ciseau something.
-西索a bois。-西索a bois。
- Ciseau a bois. - Ciseau a bois.
这是一堆"凿子"的词
That's a shitload of words for "chisel."
——凿。-进来吧。得到光明。
- Chisel. - Come on in. Get the light.
——卢米埃。——卢米埃。
- Lumiere. - Lumiere.
玛雅,晚餐。
Maya, supper.
玛雅。
Maya.
那个秃子要输得精光了。
That bald guy's gonna lose his shirt.
哦,不。
Oh, non.
是的，他们就是这么做的。
Yeah, that's how they do it.
在大曝光前切换到广告。
Cut to commercial before the big reveal.
来吧，我们吃饭吧。
Come on, let's eat.
来吧。
Come on.
你做作业了吗?
You do your homework?
——作业吗?——啊,不。
- Homework? - Ah, non.
感谢你的诚实。
Well, appreciate the honesty.
是啊，我以前也讨厌上学。
Yeah, I used to hate school, too.
讨厌它的一切。
Hated everything about it.
高中辍学，像我爸爸一样在钻机上工作，开始挖洞。
Dropped out of high school, worked a rig like my daddy, started making hole.
这就是你要做的?你要打洞吗?
That what you gonna do? You gonna make hole?
-是的，我打洞了。——没有大便。
- Oui, I make hole. - No shit.
你得从蠕虫开始，知道吗。
You got to start out a worm, you know.
这是最低级的。一个虫子。
That's the lowest of the low. A worm.
不，不是虫子。
Non, pas un worm.
我和你一样，要在derrick上工作。
Je veux travailler sur le derrick, like you.
你要直接去吊杆那儿吗?
You going right to the derrick?
你必须有想要的东西。
You got to have the want-to.
你想要吗?
You got the want-to?
本,是的。
Ben, oui.
嘿。
Hey.
主啊，感谢你的祝福。
Thank you, Lord, for this and other blessings.
请照顾好艾丽。
Please look after Ally.
好好看着她。
Keep a close eye on her.
我们奉耶稣的名祈求。
We ask this in Jesus' name.
阿们。
Amen.
——挖。——挖。
- Dig in. - Dig in.
——晚安。——晚安,妈妈。
- Bonsoir. - Bonsoir, maman.
-嗨。-嗨。
- Hey. - Hey.
-上面有个汉堡，如果你想吃的话。——谢谢。啊。
- There's a burger up there if you want it. - Thanks. Ah.
给我吗?
For me?
是的,女士。
Yes, ma'am.
——这是房租。——谢谢。
- That's rent. - Thank you.
能帮我拿一下番茄酱吗?
Would you please get me the ketchup?
非。
Non.
——“是的。——谢谢。
- Mais oui. - Thank you.
比尔，她得做家庭作业。
Bill, she has to do her homework.
我知道。百分百。
I know. Hundred percent.
做你的作业。
Do your homework.
——是吗?
- Yeah? - Mm.
谢谢。
Merci.
当我看到你们吃的东西，我就明白你们为什么祈祷。
When I see what you guys eat, I understand why you pray before.
-比赛训练怎么样?——彩排。
- How was play practice? - Rehearsal.
呃，糟透了。
Uh, it was shit.
我们写了很多舞台剧剧本，所以很混乱，还有，导演他很年轻，很外行。
We do a lot of stage writing, so it's messy, and, uh, the-the director... he's young and provincial.
舞台上写什么?
What's stage writing?
我们不知道自己在做什么，所以我们就瞎编。
We don't know what we're doing, so we make it up instead.
酷。
Cool.
酷拉乌尔。
Cool Raoul.
后退，爬到中间。
Drops back, scrambles to the middle.
在十秒内，时钟在运行，时钟在运行。
Down inside the ten, so the clock is running, clock is running.
回到床上。
Back to bed.
我和你一起看?
I look with you?
不可能。
No way.
睡觉。
Bed.
你会给我惹麻烦的。
You're gonna get me in trouble.
我的平板电脑。
My tablet.
是的，我正在用。
Yeah, I'm using it.
现在睡觉。
Bed, now.
．..第四季度。好吧,为什么不呢?
...fourth quarter. Well, why not?
喂?
Hello?
是的，就是他。
Yeah, this is him.
休假一天。
It's a one-day leave.
她早上出去，晚上回到监狱。
She goes out in the morning, comes back to the prison at night.
如果进展顺利，她下个月还能再待一天。
Then if it goes well, she'll get another day the following month.
这个想法是为了让犯人重新适应外面的世界。
The idea is for inmates to acclimate to the outside world again.
明白吗?
Understand?
是的，女士，我有。
Yes, ma'am, I do.
法官需要一个监护人，一个愿意为她担保的人。
The judge requires a chaperone, someone who is going to vouch for her.
她找我了吗?
Did she ask for me?
不。
No.
但你是唯一的选择。
But you are the only option.
好吧。艾莉森已经四个多月没跟我说话了。
Okay. A-Allison hasn't talked to me for more than four months.
我知道。
I am aware.
贝克先生，这次不要采取主动。
Mr. Baker, do not take any initiative this time.
明白吗?
Understand?
是的，女士，我有。
Yes, ma'am, I do.
嗯?
Huh?
她喜欢颜色。
Color she love.
哦，她最喜欢的颜色?
Oh, her favorite color?
啊,是的,“最喜欢的”。
Ah, oui, "favorite."
是的,不确定。
Yeah, not sure.
嘿,玛雅?
Hey, Maya?
不。
No.
我觉得它很漂亮。
I thought it was pretty.
比尔!比尔!
Bill! Bill!
啊,足球,没有。艾莉森喜欢俄克拉荷马州立大学。
Ah, soccer, no. Allison likes Oklahoma State.
她喜欢真正的足球。
She likes real football.
这是足球，最爱的脚。
This is football, favorite foot.
不，这些人只是一群孩子。
No, these guys are a bunch of babies.
群中。
Bunch of crybabies.
好了，好了，别紧张。多少钱?
All right, all right, don't get all wound up. How much?
妈妈。
Maman.
恩,非。
Euh, non.
谢谢,比尔。
Merci, Bill.
——好的。——谢谢,比尔。
- All right. - Merci, Bill.
——是的。——你好,玛雅。
- Oui. - Bonjour, Maya.
你好。
Bonjour.
嗨。你一定是比尔。
Hi. You must be Bill.
是的,先生。你好。
Yes, sir. Hi.
见到你很高兴。
Good to meet you.
维吉妮告诉我你来自俄克拉荷马。
Uh, Virginie told me you-you are from Oklahoma.
这是很酷。
That's so cool.
好吧。
Okay.
雷诺是一位冉冉升起的导演明星。
Renaud is a rising star director.
那就是我。
That's me.
你就是那个写舞台剧本的人吗?
Oh, you're the one who does the stage writing?
是的。你知道舞台写作?
Yeah. You know about stage writing?
太好了。
Great.
伙计，我真的很喜欢这样工作。
Y-You know, man, I really love working like this.
这是真的，你知道吗?
It's real, you know?
阶段写作?这是真理。
Stage writing? It's truth.
它的生命。
It's from life.
弗吉妮跟我说过，对吧?
Virginie been telling me about it, right?
是的。谢谢,比尔。
Yeah. Merci, Bill.
你能帮我搬一下桌子吗?
Um, would you help me move the table?
-因为晚餐…-好的，我知道了。
- 'Cause dinner is... - Yeah, I got it.
谢谢,比尔。
Merci, Bill.
说真的，对我来说，这完全说得通。
Seriously, for me, it makes total sense.
人们应该能够携带枪支。
People should be able to carry guns.
但他们获得了自由。
You know, but they got freedom.
它的基本自由。
It's basic freedom.
我很想有把枪。
I would love to have a gun.
我肯定你有枪。
I'm sure you have a gun.
-不是吗，比尔?-是的，先生，我知道。
- Don't you, Bill? - Yes, sir, I do.
——是的!-不，你不能。
- Yes! - No, you do not.
为什么不是我?我有两个。
Why wouldn't I? I got two of them.
我有一把猎枪和一把格洛克手枪。
I got a shotgun and a Glock.
-不，臭鼬。这不是真的。——两枪!它是完美的!
- Oh, non, putain. C'est pas vrai. - Two guns! It's perfect!
不,不。Arrete arrte。没关系。没关系。
Non, non. Arrete, arrte. It's okay. It's okay.
这是他没办法……-他…他的文化。——文化。
It's-it's his... - His-his... his culture. - Culture.
文化是一个很宽泛的概念，对吧?
Culture is such a broad concept, huh?
今晚就到此为止吧，各位。
I'm gonna call it a night, y'all.
来吧,比尔。它的早期。
Come on, Bill. It's early.
-我去哄玛雅睡觉-哦，我能行。
- I'll put Maya to bed. - Oh, I can do it.
-我知道了。——好的。
- I got it. - Okay.
你是我的最爱。
You're my favorite.
最喜欢什么?
Favorite what?
最喜欢的美国人。
Favorite American.
做个好梦，小姑娘。
Sweet dreams, little girl.
你知道现在是周日早上吧?
You know it's Sunday morning, right?
你的朋友在哪里?
Where's your friend?
哦，他今天早上很早就走了。
Oh, he left early this morning.
。
Mm.
我们喝多了。
We had a bit too much to drink.
没有大便。
Ain't no shit.
我在想，我想带艾莉森来家里看看。
I was thinking, uh, I'd like to bring Allison by the house.
对她来说不会太过了吧?
Won't it be too much for her?
我想让她看看我住的地方。
I'd like her to see where I live.
如果你不介意的话。
If you're okay with it.
我为什么不会呢?
Why wouldn't I be?
不是每个人都是。
Not everybody is.
-嗨。-嗨。
- Hey. - Hey.
你的车吗?
This your van?
从工作。
From work.
什么工作?
What work?
建设。
Construction.
我在信里跟你说过了。
I told you about it in my letters.
你没拿到吗?
You didn't get them?
我做到了。
I did.
我没有读。
I didn't read them.
-你想走了吗?-是的。
- You want to get going? - Yeah.
谢谢。
Merci.
生活是残酷的。
Life is brutal.
我可以开车吗?
Can I drive?
我被兄弟们所牺牲
♪ I've been sacrificed by brothers ♪
♬被爱人钉死在十字架上
♪ Crucified by lovers ♪
♪但是经过这一切……♪
♪ But through it all... ♪
我有段时间没听到这首歌了。
I haven't heard this song in a while.
今天的特别播放列表。
Special playlist for today.
那东西有多久了?
How old is that thing?
它仍然有效。
It still works.
♪当我有那种模糊的感觉的时候当我…♪
♪ When I get that foggy feeling when I'm... ♪
所以你没回家?
So you never went home?
不。
Nope.
如何来吗?
How come?
但是很难让人相信
♪ But it's hard to keep believing ♪
我甚至会出来
♪ I'll even come out even ♪
♬当雨水敲打着你在地上的希望♬
♪ While the rain beats your hope in the ground ♪
今晚它真的下来了
♪ And tonight it's really coming down ♪
♪我…♪
♪ I'm... ♪
你确定我们可以把车停在这里吗?
Are you sure we can park here?
他们会怎么做?
What are they gonna do?
逮捕我?
Arrest me?
O.M.
你现在真的是本地人了。
You really are a local now.
玛雅说服了我
Maya sold me on it.
那是她最喜欢的球队。
That's her favorite team.
这孩子有父亲吗?
Does this kid have a father?
他不是。
He's not around.
住在海滩什么的。
Lives on a beach or some shit.
Groovy。
Groovy.
这个女人是你的女朋友吗?
So is this woman your girlfriend?
不是那样的。
It's not like that.
我只是和他们住在一起。
I just live with them.
喜欢的室友。
Like roommates.
她是做什么的?
What does she do?
她算是个演员。
She's sort of an actress.
算是演员吗?
Sort of an actress?
她一个脱衣舞女?
She a stripper?
不。
No.
她只是不演电视剧什么的。
She just don't do TV acting or anything.
她做的剧院。
She does theater.
剧院。
Theater.
你看过她的表演吗?
Have you seen her act?
我他妈在剧院里能干什么?
What am I gonna do in a fucking theater?
是的。
Yeah.
你知道什么是糟糕的吗?
You know what's messed-up?
我一直没机会哀悼她。
I never had a chance to mourn her.
莉娜。
Lina.
我们第一次见面的时候很紧张。
It was so intense when we first met.
她很有趣。
She was so funny.
又酷又漂亮。
And cool and beautiful.
然后她搬进来了，一切都搞砸了。
Then she moved in, and everything got fucked-up.
她开始和别人上床。
She started sleeping with other people.
就像这无关紧要一样。
Like it didn't matter.
好像她只是在利用我。
Like she was just using me.
什么的。
Or something.
我觉得很丢脸。
And I felt so humiliated.
但是，你知道，真正糟糕的是…
But, you know, the really fucked-up thing is...
．..我只是想见她。
...I just want to see her.
我只想和她在一起。
I just want to be with her.
这么多。
So much.
是的。
Oui.
是啊。
Ouais.
啊!
Ah!
不,不,不!
Non, non, non!
-你好。-你好。-我是艾莉森。
- Bonjour. - Bonjour. - This is Allison.
谢谢,爸爸。我想她知道这一点。
Thanks, Dad. I think she knew that.
我是维吉尼。
I'm Virginie.
我是艾莉森。
I'm Allison.
——很高兴认识你。
- Enchantee. - Enchantee.
- - - - - -。进来。——谢谢。
- Come. Come in. - Merci.
玛雅?玛雅?
Maya? Maya?
离开这里。
Get out here.
等等。参加。
Wait. Attends.
是啊。
Ouais.
是的。
Oui.
是啊。
Ouais.
是的。
Oui.
嘿,你们。
Hey, y'all.
-啊，小心。它是热的。它是热的。——噢,…-是的。那就拿着这个。-我知道了。
- Ah, watch out. It's hot. It's hot. - Ow, that's... - Yeah. Well, then take this. - I got it.
我得到了它。我得到了它。我得到了它。
I got it. I got it. I got it.
让我们祈祷。
Let's pray.
主啊，谢谢你，为这一切祝福。
Thank you, Lord, for this and many other blessings.
谢谢你陪艾丽度过这个特别的日子。
Thank you for this special day with Ally.
我们奉耶稣的名祷告。阿们。
In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
玛雅?
Maya?
挖。
Dig in.
-就是这样。——谢谢。
- There you go. - Merci.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你们俩真的没做爱吗?
So you two really aren't having sex?
埃里森·贝克。
Allison Baker.
什么?什么?
What? What?
你现在是法国人了，我以为可以在餐桌上谈论性。
You're so French now, I-I thought it was okay to talk about sex at the dinner table.
对不起。
Sorry.
它是好吗?
Is it okay?
食物。
The food.
说实话，这是我这么长时间以来吃过的最好的一餐。
It's honestly the best meal I've had in a really long time.
好。
Good.
而且，不，我们不做爱。
And, no, we don't have sex.
耶稣。
Jesus.
是的。
Oui.
你今天在哪里吃的午饭?
So where did you have lunch today?
——披萨。——披萨?
- Pizza. - Pizza?
——在Sauveur。那是我最喜欢的地方。——哦。
- Chez Sauveur. It's my favorite place. - Oh.
——是吗?-太好吃了。
- Yeah? - It's so good.
我很好奇，你为什么来马赛学习?
And, uh, I'm curious, why did you come to Marseille to study?
那地方很远。
It was far away.
和完全不同的。
And completely different.
和披萨。
And the pizza.
我也喜欢它。
I like it, too.
嗯,哦,不。
Uh, oh, no.
他是一个称。
He's a fuckup.
一直都是。
Always has been.
墙这边更漂亮。
It's more beautiful on this side of the wall.
我喜欢他们。
I like them.
小薇吉妮和玛雅。
Virginie and Maya.
你所拥有的一切都很好。
It's good what you have.
我只是想把事情做好。
I'm just trying to do it right.
我真为你高兴，爸爸。
I'm happy for you, Dad.
——晚安。——晚安。
- Bonsoir. - Bonsoir.
嘿。
Hey.
你好吗?
How are you doing?
很好。
Pretty good.
是吗?
Yeah?
天气不错吧?
The day was nice?
飞过。
Flew by.
谢谢。
Merci.
为什么?
Pourquoi?
一切,我猜。
Everything, I guess.
哦。晚安。
Oh. Bonne nuit.
晚安，各位。
Good night.
喂?
Hello?
原谅我。
Excuse me.
我是比尔·贝克，艾莉森·贝克的父亲，来自波梅特。
I'm Bill Baker, father of Allison Baker, from Baumettes.
她怎么了?
What happened to her?
这是什么意思?
What does that mean?
我滚蛋。
Fuck off me.
我不离开你，你也不要离开我。
I don't leave you, you don't leave me.
她是好吗?
Is she okay?
她是稳定的。
She's stable.
嗨,比尔。
Hey, Bill.
我又和莎伦谈过了，告诉她你回来了。
I talked to Sharon again, told her you was back in here.
工作进展顺利。
And work's been going good.
嗯…一群好人。
Uh... good group of guys.
16、17、18、16……啊,比尔。
16, 17, 18, 16... Ah, Bill.
怎么，我搞砸了吗?
What, did I mess it up?
是的，你搞砸了。
Oui, you messed it up.
“一见钟情。
"Love at first sight.
我被你看我的眼神给困住了。”
I was trapped by how you looked at me."
卢米埃。
Lumiere.
光。
Light.
Casquette。
Casquette.
帽。
Cap.
眼镜。
Glasses.
卢内特。
Lunettes.
谢谢你，汉德。
Merci, hand.
马蒂尔德……
Mathilde...
啊。谢谢。
Ah. Merci.
你觉得怎么样?
So, what did you think?
我怎么想?
What'd I think?
是的。的玩。你觉得怎么样?
Yeah. Of the play. What did you think?
哦，很好，是的。
Oh, it was good, yeah.
是吗?好是什么?
Yeah? What was good?
嗯…我他妈不知道。我对戏剧一窍不通。
Well... I don't fucking know. I don't know shit about plays.
-而且都是法语的-别这样，比尔。一件事。
- Plus, it's all in French. - Oh, come on, Bill. One thing.
嗯…没人能像真人一样站着。
Um... Uh, no one stands like real people.
——什么?-只是看起来怪怪的。
- What? - It just looks weird.
听着，这很好，我确定。
Look, it's great, I'm sure.
别问我。
I don't... D-Don't-don't ask me.
-我是个笨蛋。-不，你不是。
- I'm a dumbass. - No, you're not.
不，这并不好，不。
And, no, it's not great, no.
啊,谢谢。
Ah, merci.
欢呼。
Cheers.
我会说，你真的很棒。
I will say, you were... really good.
这是最棒的。
Best thing up there.
我有个激动人心的消息。
So, I got exciting news.
我得到那个角色了。
I got the part.
-在电视上?——嗯。
- On the TV show? - Mm-hmm.
-是啊，我答应了。——没有大便。
- Yeah, and I said I'd do it. - No shit.
——太好了。-是的。
- That's great. - Yeah.
但是…薪水更高，但工作时间也更长，这意味着我得请保姆，我也会离开玛雅更久。
But... it's more money, but it's also more hours, so that means I'll have to pay for a babysitter and I'll be away more from Maya.
我也可以帮玛雅的忙。
Well, I could help with Maya, too.
不，你已经帮得够多了，知道吗?
No, you help enough, you know?
你有工作了。你忙吧。
You got a job. You're busy.
我也不在乎我想。
I don't care. I want to.
为什么?
Why?
——为什么?
- Why? - Mm.
我喜欢和她在一起。
I like spending time with her.
对我也一样吗?
And with me, too?
是的。
Yeah.
和你。
And you, too.
你有多喜欢它?
How much do you enjoy it?
很多。
A lot.
我想说很多。
I would say a lot.
这对我们来说将是一个重大的改变。
This would be a serious change for us.
想它会。
Guess it would.
你猜吗?
You guess?
我是说，我知道。
Well, I mean, I know.
哦。
Oh.
你知道……什么?
And you know... what?
看在上帝的份上。
Ah, for fuck's sake.
你有现金吗?
Do you have cash?
是的。是的。
Yeah. Yeah.
额，多少钱?
Uh, how much is it?
60岁。
Sixty.
没有狗屎?
No shit?
-嗨。-嗨。
- Hey. - Hey.
这是你的音乐。
This is your music.
-是的。-是的。
- Yeah. - Yeah.
有点悲哀，不是吗?也许我…-当然不是。——嗯?
I-It's a bit sad, no? Maybe I... - Ah, hell no. - Huh?
-不，很漂亮。——是吗?
- No, it's beautiful. - Yeah?
是的，你可以跟着它跳舞。
Yeah, you can dance to it.
真的吗?
Really?
不,不,不。到这里来。
No, no, no. Come here.
到这里来。
Come here.
我将向您展示。
I'll show you.
-你指给我看?-好，我带你去。
- You show me? - Yeah, I'll show you.
♬过来躺在我身边
♪ Come and lay down by my side ♪
我是塞米·史密斯。
This is Sammi Smith.
♪一直到天亮♪
♪ Till the early morning light ♪
♪我所占用的只是你的时间♪
♪ All I'm taking is your time ♪
♬帮我度过黑夜……♪
♪ Help me make it through the night... ♪
有人在盯着我们。
Oh, we got eyes on us.
本……不。
Ben... Non.
是的。
Oui.
来吧。
Viens.
♬让魔鬼带走明天♬
♪ Let the devil take tomorrow ♪
♪但是今晚我需要一个朋友♪
♪ But tonight I need a friend ♪
嘿。
Hey.
-准备好了吗?——嗯。
- Ready for it? - Mm-hmm.
昨天已经逝去，♪
♪ Yesterday is dead and gone ♪
♪明天已经走远…♪
♪ And tomorrow's out of sight... ♪
-嗨。——嗯?
- Hey. - Huh?
-我有事要问你。——什么?
- I need to ask you something. - What?
你真的有枪吗?
Do you really own a gun?
哦。
Oh.
两枪。
Two guns.
——嘿,玛雅。——嗯?
- Hey, Maya. - Hmm?
把我的头盔递给我?
Want to hand me my casque?
我的盔。我的头盔。我的安全帽。
My casque. My helmet. My hard hat.
——哦。-你能帮我拿过来吗?
- Oh. - Will you get it for me?
是的,女士。
Yes, ma'am.
是啊!
Ouais!
我们开始吧。
Here we go.
哇!
Whoa!
哦。
Oh.
哇。
Wow.
该死，这地方越来越热了。
Damn, the place is heating up.
——什么?-很多粉丝。
- Quoi? - A lot of fans.
坚果。
Going nuts.
应该有人告诉他们，他们赢了。
Someone should tell them they're winning.
好了，我们走吧。
All right, let's go.
原谅,原谅,原谅。
Pardon, pardon, pardon.
比尔。
Bill.
我好像看到一个工作上的朋友。
Oh, I think I see a friend from work.
想看看是不是他。
Want to see if it's him.
好了，我们去开货车。
Okay, let's go get the van.
-是你朋友吗?-不，那不是他
- Is it your friend? - No, that wasn't him.
-嗨。-嗨。
- Hey. - Hey.
-最近怎么样?——呃,好的。比赛刚刚结束。
- How's it going? - Uh, good. Game just ended.
很快回家。
Be home soon.
-好吧，慢慢来。——这是妈妈吗?
- Okay, take your time. - C'est maman?
-今晚属于你——好的。
- It's your night. - Okay.
呃，一会儿见。
Uh, see you in a bit.
Wouah !
Wouah!
回去睡觉吧。
Go back to sleep.
继续。
Go on.
我们要回家了。
We're going home.
Ca。
Ca va.
贝克先生。
Mr. Baker.
很高兴再次见到你。
Nice to see you again.
你迟到了。
You're late.
哦。
Oh.
Excusez-moi。
Excusez-moi.
我能为你做什么，贝克先生?
What can I do for you, Mr. Baker?
我们说过的那个DNA测试我想尽快完成。
That DNA test we talked about... I want to get it done.
首先，我需要DNA样本。
First I will need, uh, the DNA sample.
我能问问你是怎么弄到这个的吗?
Can I ask you how you got this?
你到底能不能做到?
Can you do it or not?
是的,我能。
Yes, I can.
但我以前是警察，所以我告诉你，为了证明你女儿的清白而犯罪将是一个严重的错误。
But I am an ex-cop, so let me tell you, it will be a serious mistake to commit a crime to prove your daughter innocent.
这也救不了她。
It will not get her out of jail.
它会把你送进去。
And it will send you in.
-你明白吗?-你能多快?
- Do you understand? - How fast can you do it?
这很难说。
It's hard to say.
至少一个星期，但要花你不少钱。
A week at least, but it will cost you.
这是3000年了。
Here's 3,000 now.
你完成后我会再给你三千块，但肯定比一周快。
I'll give you another 3,000 when you get it done, but it's got to be quicker than a week.
就算匹配，我也得找到这个人。
Even if it matches, I still have to find this guy.
不,你没有。
No, you don't.
你知道他在哪吗?
You know where he is?
他还是有可能在结果出来之前消失。
He could still disappear before the results come back.
他不会。搞定后给我打电话。
He won't. Call me when you get it done.
来吧。
Come on.
玛雅?
Maya?
嘿,玛雅?
Hey, Maya?
嘿。
Hey.
-这真是一种问候。-你看到玛雅了吗?
- This is quite a greeting. - You seen Maya?
-我在洗澡。-是的。
- I was in the shower. - Yeah.
她正在院子里踢足球。
She's playing soccer in the courtyard.
对不起，我迟到了。
I'm sorry I'm late.
-哦，没关系。——……你不想问我第一天上班的情况吗?
- Oh, that's all right. - It... Don't you want to ask me about my first day at work?
嗯,是的,是的。怎么去了?
Uh, yeah, yeah. How'd it go?
——比尔?——嗯?
- Bill? - Hmm?
山洞里的那个人是谁?
Who is the man in the cave?
在山洞里吗?
In the cave?
用的工具。
With the tools.
我看见他。
I saw him.
我需要你的帮助。
Um, I'm gonna need your help.
好吧?
Okay?
因为这是个秘密。
'Cause it's a secret.
你不能告诉任何人。
You can't tell anyone.
甚至你的妈妈。
Even your mom.
好吧?
Okay?
他是个坏人。
He's a bad man.
他马上就走了。
He'll be gone soon.
这是我们之间的秘密。
It's gonna be our secret.
好吧?
Okay?
这是我的女孩。
That's my girl.
大便。
Shit.
事实上，我学到了一些新东西。
I learned something new actually.
这对我帮助很大。
It's helped me a lot.
这东西叫"浴缸"
It's something called the "Mektub."
一个护士告诉我的。
A nurse told me about it.
它是关于接受。
It's about acceptance.
接受什么?
Acceptance of what?
你的命运。
Your fate.
它帮我停止挣扎。
It's helping me to stop struggling so much.
停止质疑一切。
Stop questioning everything.
你只要拥抱你的命运，学会平静地生活。
You just embrace your fate and learn to live in peace with it.
这是穆斯林的想法。
It's a Muslim idea.
它是关于放弃所有的羞愧和内疚，这些让你沮丧，让你感到无助。
It's about... letting go of all of that...shame...and guilt that pushes you down and keeps you down and makes you feel so powerless.
在很长一段时间里，我都是这种感觉。
And that's how I felt for a really long time.
无能为力和遗忘。
Powerless and forgotten.
这让生活变得非常艰难。
And... that makes living really hard.
你懂我的意思吗?
You know what I mean?
但是你是无辜的。
But you're innocent.
所以我们要继续战斗。
So we got to keep fighting.
我是无辜的并不重要，爸爸。
It doesn't matter that I'm innocent, Dad.
这与正义无关。
It's not about justice.
这是关于寻找平静。
It's about finding peace.
我不知道你在说什么，但你是在白费口舌。
I don't know what you're saying, but you're wasting your breath.
等DNA出来了，我们就知道了。
We're gonna wait for that DNA, and then we'll know.
她问我。她付给我。
She ask me. She pay me.
你还要水吗?
You want more water?
艾莉森，她说，去吧。你把莉娜弄晕了。”
Allison, she say, "Go. You put Lina out."
-够了，现在。-“给你钱。”
- That's enough, now. - "Money for you."
这就够了,现在。
That's enough, now.
她让我拿着。
She tell me take it.
她给了我科利尔。
She gave me collier.
“你把它。
"You take it.
——钱。”——在这里。
- Money after." - Here.
喝。
Drink that.
继续。
Go on.
联合国科利尔。“你自己拿去吧。”
Un collier. "You take it for you."
科利尔。黄金。
Collier. Gold.
像这样。像这样。
Like this. Like this.
这条项链吗?我不想那样。
The necklace? I-I don't want that.
不!
No!
她给了我。
She gave me.
她说,“走吧。你把莉娜弄晕了。
She say, "Go. You put Lina out.
现在的项链。钱后。”
Necklace now. Money after."
你根本说不通。
You're not even making sense.
是时候闭嘴了。
Time to shut the fuck up.
S-Stillwater !
S-Stillwater!
你想说什么?
What'd you say?
科利尔。
The collier.
他说“静”。
He say "Stillwater."
黄金。
Gold.
她说……“这样做。让她走了。
She say... "Do it. Make her go.
让她出去。”
Make her go out."
嘿。
Hey.
-嗨。-你去哪儿了?
- Hey. - Where were you?
我从波梅特家走回来的。
I walked back from the, uh, Baumettes.
我们得去见伊莎贝尔。
We have to go and see Isabelle.
如果我们现在不走，就会迟到。
We'll be late if we don't leave now.
做的,嗯…我一定要走吗?
Do, uh... do I have to go?
是的,当然。
Yes, of course.
我告诉她你要来。
I told her you were coming.
请快点。玛雅……
Hurry up, please. Maya...
是的,妈妈。
Oui, maman.
伊莎贝尔就像是我们的教母。
So, Isabelle is a sort of like godmother for us.
玛雅真的很爱她。
Maya really loves her.
好吧,你会看到。
Well, you'll see.
这真是马赛的另一边。
This is really the other side of Marseille.
Marraine !
Marraine!
啊。
Ah.
我不知道你在说什么。
I don't know what you're talking about.
她离开那天我送她的金项链。
The gold necklace I gave her the day she left.
上面写着"静水"
Said "Stillwater" on it.
是的，我记得。什么呢?
Yeah, I remember it. What about it?
你还记得吗，她在庭审时戴着它吗?
D-Do you remember, was she wearing it at the trial?
她还戴着吗?
Did she still have it on?
你在搞什么，比尔?
What are you getting into, Bill?
我们去拿她的东西的时候，你看到了吗?
Wh-When we went to get her stuff, did you see it?
哦，我不知道。
Oh, I don't know.
我不记得了。为什么?
I don't remember. Why?
我晚点再打给你，莎伦。再见。
I'll talk to you later, Sharon. Bye.
弗吉尼亚州吗?
Ca va?
是的。是的,ca。
Yeah. Yeah, ca va.
跟莎伦说话。
Uh, talking to Sharon.
-她还好吗?-是的，她很好。
- Is she okay? - Yeah, yeah, she's fine.
是吗?
Are you?
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
你看起来心不在焉。
You just seem distrait.
我是。对不起。
I am. Sorry.
我很高兴你在这里。
I'm happy you're here.
我也是。
Me, too.
你也吗?
You, too?
你很高兴你在这里?
Y-You're-you're happy you're here?
——是吗?——我。
- Yeah? - I am.
真的。
Really.
我也是。
Me, too.
我喜欢你，比尔·贝克。
I like you, Bill Baker.
好的,来了。
Okay, come.
迪罗莎先生，我是比尔·贝克。
Mr. Dirosa, it's Bill Baker.
我真的很需要那个结果。
Uh, really need that result.
呃，有点紧急。
Uh, it's kind of urgent.
您好,夫人。
Bonjour, madame.
你好。
Bonjour.
女佣journee。
Bonne journee.
再见。
Au revoir.
你知道吗，我小时候在学校也经常打架。
You know, I used to fight a lot at school when I was a kid, too.
但这并不好。战斗?不。
But that's not good. Fight? No.
你确定不要吗?
You sure you don't want this?
山洞里的那个人，你要杀了吗?
The man in the cave, you will kill?
什么?不。
What? No.
当然不是。
Of course not.
我永远不会做任何伤害你和你母亲的事。
I would never, ever do anything to hurt you or your mother.
从来没有。
Never.
因为我爱你们两个。
Because I love both of you.
这么多。
So much.
我做的事。
I do.
你只要相信我就行了
You just have to trust me.
好吧?
Okay?
好吧。
Okay.
贝克先生，有话跟你说。
Mr. Baker, a word please.
警察。
Police.
我能看一下您的身份证吗?
Can I see your I.D. please?
你的身份证，贝克先生。
Your I.D., Mr. Baker.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
摘下你的帽子。
Take off your cap.
好吧。谢谢你！
Okay. Thank you.
贝克先生，我的同事们要把这个小女孩带进去。
So, Mr. Baker, my colleagues are gonna take the little girl inside.
好吧?
Okay?
——不,比尔。-好吧，好吧，好吧。
- No, Bill. - Okay, all right, all right, all right.
没关系。没关系。
It's okay. It's all right.
-你跟她去——没有。
- You go with her. - No.
万事快调。万事快调。
Tout va bien. Tout va bien.
没关系。
It's all right.
你都是对的。
You're all right.
贝克先生，看着我。
So, Mr. Baker, look at me.
你们这里有地下室吗?
Do you have a basement here?
是或否?
Yes or no?
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
好吧。请把钥匙给我。
Okay. Give me the keys please.
请。
Please.
停。
Stop.
你有钥匙吗?
Do you have the key?
贝克先生。
Mr. Baker.
他有它。
He's got it.
让我们上楼。
Let's go upstairs.
坐下。
Sit.
来吧。
Viens.
去吧，亲爱的
Vas-y, cherie.
是的。
Oui.
——是的。——啊。
- Oui. - Ah.
是的。
Oui.
啊。
Ah.
——非?——不。
- Non? - Non.
——是的。
- Oui. - Mm.
好吧。
Okay.
Virginie，我不是故意的…你怎么找到他的?
Virginie, I didn't mean to... How did you find him?
纯粹的机会。
Pure chance.
足球比赛。
The soccer game.
玛雅?
With Maya?
你让她撒谎了吗?
Did you ask her to lie?
是吗?
Did you?
我从没想过把你和玛雅牵扯进来。
I never meant to involve you or Maya.
——我知道…——你……
- I know... - You...
你现在得走了。
You have to leave now.
好吧。你收拾东西走人。
Okay. You pack your things, you leave.
我可以进来吗?
May I come in?
玛雅?
Maya?
你不想跟我说话吗?
You don't want to talk to me?
好吧。
All right.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
我爱你。
I love you.
比尔。
Bill.
非。
Non.
贝克先生，我带来了一个特别的消息。
Mr. Baker, I've come with some extraordinary news.
你女儿案子的法官今早给我打电话了。
The judge in your daughter's case called me this morning.
新的证据已经浮出水面。
New evidence has surfaced.
显然，一个退休警察找到了与未知样本匹配的DNA。
Apparently, a retired cop came up with a DNA match on the unknown sample.
它也与四年前警方在一桩入室盗窃案中收集的样本相符。
It also matched a sample the police collected on a burglary case four years ago, after the trial.
他们抓到他了吗?
Did they catch him?
不,还没有。
No, not yet.
但我们需要证明的只是足够的怀疑。
But all we need to prove is sufficient doubt.
所以即使他们找不到嫌疑人，他们也很有可能会释放艾莉森。
So even if they can't find the suspect, there's a real chance they will release Allison.
事实上，法官已经同意重新调查，这几乎是闻所未闻的。
In fact, the judge has already agreed to reopen the investigation, which is almost unheard of.
我认为这只会发生在马赛。
I think this could only happen in Marseille.
谢谢你来告诉我，夫人。
Thank you for coming to tell me, ma'am.
贝克先生，这对你的家庭来说可能是最好的结果。
Mr. Baker, this is the best possible outcome for your family.
你明白吗?
Do you understand?
我做的事。
I do.
谢谢你,女士。
Thank you, ma'am.
去,会!
Go, Pokes!
我告诉过你我们会把女儿带回家的，我们确实这么做了。
I told you we were gonna bring our girl home, and that's exactly what we did.
欢迎回家,埃里森。
Welcome home, Allison.
欢迎回到俄克拉荷马州。
Welcome back to Oklahoma.
欢迎回到美国!
Welcome back to America!
你是反社会?
You're being antisocial?
你对吧?
You all right?
你去马赛那天，莎伦和我开车送你去机场，到了机场后，我觉得很尴尬，因为我没有礼物，所以我去了礼品店。
The day you left for Marseille, Sharon and I drove you to the airport, and... when we got there, I was embarrassed I didn't have a present or nothing, so I went to the gift shop.
我想给你买本书或者钥匙链什么的。
I thought I'd get you a book or a key chain or something.
然后我看到了这条项链。
Then I saw this necklace.
我以为你会把它当成一个小小的家。
I thought it'd be like a little piece of home to take with you.
这是黄金。
It was gold.
上面写着"静水"
Said "Stillwater" on it.
我不希望发生这种事。
I didn't want it to happen.
他说他会帮我把她弄出公寓，仅此而已。
He told me that he would just help me get her out of the apartment, that's all.
我不想让她死。
I didn't want her to die.
我爱她。
I loved her.
我知道。
I know you did.
你觉得我是个怪物?
You think I'm a monster?
你是我的女儿。
You're my daughter.
我…我从来没有那样想过。
I... I could never think that.
爸爸，我们怎么了?
Dad, what is wrong with us?
我不知道，宝贝。
I don't know, baby girl.
我不知道。
I don't know.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
我也是。
Me, too.
♬把我头发上的缎带拿开♬
♪ Take the ribbon from my hair ♪
♪松开它，让它掉下来♪
♪ Shake it loose and let it fall ♪
♬把它轻轻地放在你的皮肤上
♪ Lay it soft against your skin ♪
♪就像墙上的影子……♪
♪ Like the shadows on the wall... ♪
早....
Morning.
嘿。
Hey.
睡不着。
Couldn't sleep.
去散步，最后来到了这里。
Went for a walk, and... ended up here.
我很高兴你这么做了。
I'm glad you did.
你想念他们吗?
You miss them?
我做的事。
I do.
你能回去吗?
Can you go back?
不,我不能。
No, I can't.
但这很好。
But it was good.
不改变。
That don't change.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
生活是残酷的。
Life is brutal.
这里的一切看起来都一样。
Everything looks the same here.
什么都没有改变。
Nothing's changed.
你不觉得吗?
Don't you think?
不，艾丽，我没有。
No, Ally, I don't.
在我看来，一切都不一样了。
It all looks different to me.
我都认不出来了。
I don't hardly recognize it anymore.